Jeremy Quijano

□ 909-543-8510 • ☑ jeremykquijano@gmail.com • **in** jeremyquijano • • ☐ JeremyQuijano

Summary

BS in Physics. I recently left my Astrophysics graduate program to pursue opportunities in Data Science, Machine Learning, and Python Development. My research focus was applying Machine Learning to Astrophysics and novel problems. I have 6 years of Python and 5 years of Machine Learning experience in a research environment from undergraduate and graduate work. I have 3 years of Data Science experience from research and Data Science fellowships. Several of my projects can be found on my GitHub. Contact me via phone or email for more information.

Skills

Programming

• Python 3, Jupyter Notebook/Lab, Anaconda, PyCharm, Google Colab, GitHub, C++, VS Code

Data Science

• Machine Learning, TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, Deep Learning, SciKit-Learn, NumPy, Pandas, SciPy

Data Visualization/Presentation

• Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Microsoft Excel/Powerpoint, Google Sheets/Slides, Apple Numbers/Keynote

General Computing

• MacOS, Windows 10/11, PC Hardware, Word Processors: Microsoft Word/Google Docs/LaTeX (Overleaf)

Education	
University of South Alabama (USA) • Computer Science Graduate Student	August 2024 – Present <i>GPA: N/A</i>
The University of Alabama (UA) • Some Graduate Coursework in Astrophysics	August 2020 – May 2023 <i>GPA: 2.5</i>
University of California, Riverside (UCR) • Bachelor of Science in Physics	September 2017 – June 2019 <i>GPA: 3.5</i>
Crafton Hills College (CHC) • General Coursework and Transfer Credit	August 2014 – May 2017 <i>GPA: 3.9</i>
-	

Experience

Youth Esports Coach Vanta Esports • Youth development coach for Rocket League – Part Time	February 2024 – Present
Athletics Tutor The University of Alabama • Math and Science tutor at the Bill Battle Academic Center – Part Time	January 2024 – July 2024
 Graduate Researcher The University of Alabama Research under Assistant Professor, Dr. Sergei Gleyzer Dark matter substructure analysis using strong gravitational lenses and machine learning 	June 2021 – June 2023
Graduate Teaching Assistant The University of Alabama • Instructor for Introduction to Astronomy Lab	August 2020 – May 2021
Undergraduate Researcher University of California, Riverside	September 2018 - June 2019

- Research under Associate Professor, Dr. George Becker Unpaid
- Research experience and senior thesis project

Achievements	/ Awards
/ tollica cilicito	, , tttala

October 2021 - July 2023 **UA** | LSSTC Data Science Fellowship • LSSTC Data Science Fellow sponsored by Northwestern University **UA** | Southern Regional Education Board Fellowship August 2021 - June 2023 • SREB State Doctoral Scholars Program member • Provides support for minorities pursuing PhD's and continuing in academia CHC/UCR | Dean's List Honoree August 2014 - June 2019 Achieving a GPA of 3.5 or higher during a semester/quarter CHC | 2017 Southern California Edison STEM Scholarship recipient June 2017 Received for achieving academic excellence and continued pursuit of a STEM degree **Projects** LSSTC Data Science Fellowship October 2022 - July 2023 • Data Science projects to learn data science techniques for Astronomers Technology/Tools: Python, Jupyter Notebooks, Anaconda, Big Data, Data Science, GitHub **UA** | BINGO Probability Program August 2022 - December 2022 Probability and analysis program for Data Analysis course in Fall 2022 Technology/Tools: Python, Jupyter Notebooks, Anaconda, Data Science, GitHub June 2021 - June 2023 **UA** | Strong Gravitational Lens Finding Project Automated process for finding strong gravitational lenses using machine learning Technology/Tools: Python, Google Colab, Jupyter Notebooks, PyCharm, TensorFlow, PyTorch, PyLensing, PyAutoLens UCR | Senior Thesis: Quasar Spectra Analysis Using Machine Learning April 2019 - June 2019 • A machine learning algorithm to classify three different simulated quasar spectra Technology/Tools: Python, Jupyter Notebooks, TensorFlow, SAOImageDS9, GitHub UCR | 2D Spectral Analysis and Sigma Clipping September 2018 - April 2019 • Testing new FITS image reduction pipeline created by Dr. George Becker Technology/Tools: IDL, Python, Jupyter Notebooks, SAOImageDS9, ESO X-Shooter data, GitHub **Extracurriculars** U13+ Youth Recreational Soccer Coach • Tuscaloosa United Soccer Club **UA** | Google Summer of Code Mentor Machine Learning mentor for UA DeepLense Project

March 2024 - May 2024 June 2022 - August 2022 **UA** | Esports Club Member August 2020 - June 2022 • Rocket League player and coach for university team **UCR** | **Esports Club Member September 2017 - June 2020** Rocket League player and coach for university team August 2016 - May 2017 CHC | Physics Club Member

• Local STEM outreach